# JOSE DUARTE E SILVA

pt.linkedin.com/in/joseduartesilva

mobile: (00 351) · 914 285 059 ♦ Email: jcarlosduartesilva@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Senior manager with 14 years of experience, focused on creating business solutions (e-commerce, retail, banking and fintech) for international organizations, with strong ability to deal with complex environments, strategic challenges and manage all level stakeholders. I am centered on people, and strongly believe that investing in Engineering Culture results in high performance teams, enabling the business growth by delivering better and faster.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **FARFETCH**

Head of Engineering

since February 2023

- · Creating and leading Marketplace Services domain (2 clusters with 6 multi-disciplinar teams, including Principals, Eng. Leads and Managers) leveraging Farfetch Platform with Domain Driven design for Marketplace native consumers (Android, iOS and Web)
- · Stakeholders management and business alignment driver pivoting Operations and Engineering (Architecture, Product, Infra, Data & MLE, etc)
- · Portofolio and dependencies manager, Capacity planner
- · Stakeholder and contributor to the Farfetch Purchase (Promotions & Checkout), Fintech (Fraud, Payments & Refunds) and Discovery & Navigation (Search, Catalog and Recommendations) vision

Senior Engineering Manager

May 2018 - February 2023

- · Responsible for several Consumer Products Web clusters (Personalization & Inspiration, Discovery & Navigation), often with more than one (+70 team elements)
- · Leading Farfetch Platform's Loyalty and FinTech clusters (Benefits, Segments, Promotions, Payments & Refunds)
- · Owner of the areas roadmap and software life-cycle (including incident management), Engineering Culture developer and Quality promoter

## **BIT - SONAE**

Area Manager Digital Coordinator

February 2017 - May 2018

- · Leading multidisciplinary teams on the delivery of e-commerce applications
- · Agile driver, implementing SCRUM, Continuous Integration & Delivery
- · Manage key stakeholders for different programs and initiatives (Order and Warehouse management system for online orders, design and delivery of Worten's Marketplace)
- · Responsible for the business and tech roadmap execution

- · Defining and auditing Quality processes and methodologies
- · Managing the external Quality service provider
- · Budget management

## **BETFAIR - BLIP**

Delivery Manager

October 2015 - April 2016

- $\cdot$  Leading a multidisciplinary team on the delivery of high quality & performance applications Sportsbook Platform
- · Agile driver, implementing SCRUM, Continuous Integration & Delivery

### **ROCKET-INTERNET - JUMIA**

Head of Quality Assurance

April 2012 - September 2015

- · Auditing and implementing Quality processes and methodologies (Continuous Integration & Delivery System) in worldwide e-commerce companies (e.g. Kaymu, Jumia, Jovago, Lazada, Zalando)
- · Quality team and company performance monitoring, working closely with MDs, CTOs and CPOs to align the business and management needs

#### **BEU.BI**

Quality Assurance Manager

April 2010 - March 2012

- · Responsible for the quality of all products in the bank sector and the Quality team
- · Responsible for the implementation of Test Management Process

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION**

### SQS Portugal, Lisbon

2011

ISTQB Certified Tester, Foundation Level

## University of Aveiro

2009

M.S. in Computers and Telematics Engineering (3 grade incomplete)